I'm reminded of a friend's story. He
had started a very good SIP for his child. But when he suddenly passed away, the family faced such financial difficulties that
they had to not only stop the SIP but also withdraw all the funds.
So, the child's college fund was gone. Yes, the true value of this plan
is revealed when life doesn't go according to plan. It's not just about money
. It's about the assurance that your child's
dreams won't be thwarted even in your absence. Hello friends, my name
is Anil Rajpurohit. I am the founder of Family First Financial Services. I hold an MBA in Finance and
have worked in the corporate sector for 15 years. And today, in January 2026, I
'm presenting to you. ICIC PRU Life Insurance
has launched a new guaranteed child plan called the Smart Kid 360 Plan.
While this plan is a child plan, the insurance isn't just for the child. It's for the child's
future, for their goals, for their goals. Let's understand
the key features of this plan, and I'll explain them in detail
. Please watch the entire video. If you like the video,
please like, share, and subscribe to my YouTube channel, Anil Rajpurohit FFFS. Here, you'll
find over 300 videos on insurance -related topics, whether it's a single plan, equity-based plan, term insurance plan, or
term-plus-equity plans, which will
greatly assist you in financial planning, especially insurance-related planning
. Regarding the eligibility criteria, this
policy can be purchased by individuals between 18 and 50 years of age.
Premium payments can be made for 5 years, and premium payments
can be made up to 12 years. The minimum policy term is 12 years, and the maximum policy term available is 25 years
. Premiums can be paid annually, semi-annually, and
monthly. The quarterly option
is not available with this policy. The minimum premium will depend on your premium payment. If you
opt for a short premium payment term, the minimum premium will start at ₹1.5 lakh.
And if you opt for a long premium term, such as for 12 years, you
can purchase this policy with as little as ₹30,000. Children's futures, their dreams for the future
, don't come all at once. They come at different stages of life, whether
it's school, graduation, post-graduation, or marriage. These all come at different
stages. How can this policy
be useful in a child's transition from school to college, marriage, or business startup? Whether
the parents are paying the premiums for the policy or not. How will this policy work in both cases
? We'll explain step by step. Next, ICICI PRU Life Insurance's
Star Kit 360 plan is a guaranteed plan. This is a non-linked, non-participating plan
. It's neither related to the stock market, nor is it a unit-linked policy, nor
does it participate in the company's profits, i.e., bonuses. It's a 100% guaranteed plan. When you
purchase this plan, the benefits listed in the benefit illustration on the first day
will remain the same throughout the policy term, whether the market is up or
down. Furthermore, your insurance coverage under this policy
will be for your parents. This means that if the father or mother is proposed to
be covered under the policy, the insurance coverage will be for them. The child will only
be the beneficiary, nominee, and not insured. However, the overall benefits are
designed with the child's future in mind . Here, you
can select a particular year for money back based on your child's different goals,
such as when the child turns 13, 15
, 18, or 21. I need income in these four years. I
also need income at maturity. Do you want level income or incremental income? Whether
you want four or three times the income, you
can decide this according to your needs during the entire policy term. How will you
receive this income? You will receive a certain portion of this income called the Assured Benefit. Assured Benefit
means the premium payment term plus the annual premium. Let's assume your
annual premium is ₹1 lakh and you are paying premiums for 12 years, then
your premium becomes ₹12 lakh. So, if you are receiving level income of ₹12 lakh, you
will receive 25% of this. This means you will receive ₹3 lakh in the 13th, 15th, 18th, and 21st years.
Maturity will come. Similarly, if you want to receive income for three years, three times,
then you can take 33% of 12 lakhs. Similarly, if you
want to receive income in increasing mode, then I
did not receive this 33 lakhs all at once. I need a little money in the beginning when I study in school, there
are less expenses there. But in graduation or post-graduation, marriage or business
startup, a larger amount may be needed. So you
can take the option of increasing mode. If you take four payouts, then you will get 15% for the first time,
then 20%, then 30%, then 35%. If you select income three times, then you
will get 20%, 30% and 50% of the assured benefit which you will get as income and this
will be 100% guaranteed. Among these benefits, you
'll receive a built-in waiver of premium and policy continuation benefits. You
don't need to pay any additional premium for this. This means that even if the proposed policyholder dies,
the child will receive the income and maturity proceeds. Additionally,
there's an optional family income benefit, which you
can avail by paying an additional premium. We'll explore how this works later. A 35-year-old
man has a one-year-old daughter and is considering
securing her future with a guaranteed plan. Let's explore a
benefit illustration, an example, to see how this
policy will work for him. Let's watch a short video. Then,
we'll explore the rest of the examples and benefit illustrations. Today, my daughter, Kavya, is only one year old,
but the responsibility for her future lies with me. Tomorrow, she'll need to study. She will need support for college
and to stand on her own feet. Whether I live or not,
no need in her life should remain unfulfilled. Now, a 35-year-old man with a one-year-old
daughter decides that he wants to pay premiums for 10 years.
He wants to pay ₹1 lakh annually. He is taking a policy term of 25 years. Now, he
wants that when his child completes 10th grade, starts graduation,
during post-graduation, or during a business startup, he needs money and
on maturity, whether it is for marriage or starting a big business,
he should receive a large amount and it should be guaranteed for 100 years. So, he
is planning in this way. So, if he is alive, how will the benefits come? If
unfortunately, they die—let's say they paid four premiums and then
died—I'll
explain the benefits in detail later with a benefit illustration. Before that, let me explain one thing. If you're
looking at the screen, income is available in the 16th year, 18th year, 21st year, and 24th year,
and maturity occurs when the child turns 26. Now, if
the customer wants to receive income in the 15th year instead of the 16th year, they can still do so.
This isn't a fixed pattern: 16, 18, or 21. If you take income in the 15th year, 14th year, or 15th year, you can take it.
Then, if you want to take income in the 20th, 21st, or 22nd year, you
can do so. This means you can decide which year you want to receive income. This
isn't a fixed pattern. You can receive income yearly. You
can continue to receive income for four years. And you
can also receive income after a few years. In the benefit illustrations I'm sharing,
I'm describing both scenarios: how life is going according to plan, and how your plan will work if
something unfortunate
happens. Let's understand this plan through
the benefit illustrations. Now, let's understand this plan. Along with the
benefit illustrations, I 'm going to show you three or four illustrations,
which include a level option, an increasing option,
a family income benefit, and a no-family income benefit.
Let's first take an example: a 35-year-old man
named Anil Rajput is purchasing a policy, and the purchase, insurance cover, etc.,
is his own. She's his one-year-old daughter. He's purchasing the policy for her.
His daughter will be the nominee. So, you won't see "Life to be Insured" here
because he's the insured himself. Only the nominee is his daughter. So, it's visible there. The plan's name is
ICICI Pro Smart K 360, which is a non-participating, non-linked
individual savings plan. Currently, there's no GST applicable. The GST is zero.
It's over. Let's assume the customer is paying premiums for 10 years.
They're taking a 25-year policy term and paying ₹0.5 lakh annually. So,
what's the assumed benefit? Premium payment term into annual
premium. So, if you multiply ₹0.5 lakh by 10, you get an assumed benefit of ₹25 lakh. Accordingly,
25% of ₹25 lakh, or ₹5 lakh, will come to you as income.
It will come as a money back. Here, you've seen the money backs mentioned. Which of the four money backs
is guaranteed and how much is it? What's the guaranteed maturity benefit?
You'll receive ₹42,78,000 upon maturity. This will be tax-free, and what will be the insurance cover from day one
? It will be ₹25 lakh. You'll have to give a check for your annual ₹0.5 lakh premium.
You can pay online. Now, if you look at the table here,
you'll see the guaranteed benefits written out. Let's assume a customer
is paying a premium of ₹5 lakh for 10 years. Here, you'll see that the first income
will be ₹6,25,000 in the 16th year. From the 18th year, they'll again receive a guaranteed income of ₹6,25,000.
The income is ₹25,000 in the 21st year. The income is ₹25,000 in the 24th year. And
the maturity benefit they receive in the 25th year
is a guaranteed maturity benefit of ₹42,78,000.
Now, here, you'll see what the death benefit is from day one: ₹25 lakh, which
gradually increases to ₹26,25,000. Here,
the higher of the two, Guaranteed Surrender Value and Special Surrender Value,
will be given to you as surrender benefit. Now
let's look at another scenario. In this scenario, let's understand that suppose
the customer dies. You will see that he has
not availed the Family Income Benefit. Let's assume that the customer
paid four premiums and died, then what was the insurance cover at that time? ₹25 lakh.
₹25 lakh will be given to the nominee immediately. ICICI will now pay the remaining six premiums itself,
and the income that the girl was getting, ₹6,25,000 four times,
will continue to come to the girl, and this income of ₹42,7,000 will also come at maturity. That means the family gets
25 lakh rupees plus this 25 lakh rupees, plus the annual payback, making the total 50 lakh
rupees. This 42 lakh rupees means the nominees will receive approximately 9,278,000 rupees. They
paid premiums for four years, each paying 1 lakh rupees. They
received 92 lakh rupees in return. This is how this policy works. The equity-based IRR
doesn't always work. If you're there, you'll earn your own income. So, the family won't need that much money anyway
. In that case, if you're not there, someone
is giving you a secure guarantee, that too in writing, for the next 25 years. This is a very good feature here
. Now, let's look at an optional benefit. This is a type of rider. It's
known as the Family Income Benefit. As you
saw in the example in the previous benefit illustration, the death benefit is immediately available upon death. The money back you
decided on will be returned. Premium increases are waived, and
you receive the maturity benefit. However, if you
add this rider by paying a small premium, you'll still receive the same benefits.
You'll receive an additional income benefit throughout the policy term
, representing 10% of your insurance cover, which will be paid annually.
The money back you were receiving will continue to be received. The maturity benefit will also be paid, but
you'll also receive a lump sum death benefit. Let's assume
your insurance cover was ₹25 lakh, so 10% of ₹2 lakh is ₹5 lakh. This income will continue to flow to you every year
until maturity. This income will begin the year of the proposed death
. Let's understand this by example. Let's also understand this from the benefit
illustration: the same 35-year-old man with a one-year-old daughter
purchased a policy for her. He also added a family income benefit. Now,
what impact will this have on her maturity or death? Let's understand this
from the benefit illustration. Let's consider another example. This customer
is also purchasing a policy. But this time, he has opted for the family income benefit. He
is taking the family income benefit, and
the premium is the same ₹5 lakh. He receives the same income. However, this time, the income
is around ₹40 lakh instead of ₹42 lakh. This means the income is reduced by ₹5 lakh. The premium is the same ₹5 lakh.
He is paying the premium as an additional rider. He is keeping it built-in, so he
doesn't have to pay any extra premium. So, what benefit will this customer get from this?
Let's assume the customer paid four premiums this time, and this time again, they assume
death. They will definitely receive ₹25 lakh.
The income of ₹25 lakh that was supposed to come will also come. The maturity amount of ₹40 lakh that was supposed to come will also come. However,
since death occurred in the fourth year, premiums for the remaining years are also waived. However,
from the fifth year onwards, 10% of the ₹25 lakh insurance cover, the sum
assured on inception, i.e. ₹5 lakh,
will accrue every year from the fifth year to the 25th year. For the next 20 years, ₹5 lakh will accrue as income,
known as family income. This is the benefit of this rider. Simply
put, this lump sum of ₹25 lakh
will be needed by the family in an emergency. Plus, this ₹5 lakh coming in every year is a
kind of risk transfer for the family. Because household expenses will also require money. Furthermore
, the ₹5 lakh that was earmarked for the children's education, higher education,
startup, or marriage will be separate money back and income for them.
However, this ₹2.5 lakh that is coming in can also be used for household expenses.
Now, let's take another example where the customer wants to pay a higher premium.
Because in this type of policy, if you pay a premium of up to ₹5 lakh,
the returns are tax-free. So, let me explain briefly: if
you pay a premium of ₹5 lakh for 12 years, the customer earns ₹15 lakh every year
, and at maturity, you have an income of approximately ₹96,40,000. So, the maturity amount is approximately one crore rupees
, and you get a refund of ₹60 lakh, and the insurance
cover is in place from day one. In case of death, you will receive ₹50 lakh immediately. You will receive an annual income of ₹15 lakh each
, and ₹964,600 at maturity. Now , let's consider
another example. The customer
has added a family income benefit
to this ₹5 lakh income . Let's assume the customer has added a family income benefit to the ₹5
lakh. Let's assume the customer died with a single premium
. The family receives ₹5 lakh against the ₹5 lakh. Then, since the insurance cover is in place from day one, 10% of that amount, i.e. ₹5 lakh,
will continue to be paid as family income for the next 24 years,
from the second year to the 25th year. You'll receive a money back of ₹151.5 million, along with
a maturity amount of ₹895,600. Let's take a final example. After that,
I'll illustrate your benefits here. I think you
'll understand the entire plan easily. Let's assume the same customer purchasing the policy. But this time,
they're not taking a level income. They're taking an increasing income, and they
're not taking the income for four years; they're taking it for only three years. So, they
pay ₹500,000 for 12 years
. In their 70th year, they decide to receive an income of ₹120,000
. They decide to receive another income of ₹180,000 in their 19th year
. And they decide to receive a larger income of ₹100,000 in their 21st year . And finally, in the 25th year, they
will receive a tax-free maturity benefit of ₹9,68,420. This is all while they are alive. In the event of death,
the family will receive the death benefit immediately, and the remaining premiums will be waived.
This income will continue, and maturity will also be available. I hope you
can easily understand this benefit illustration. Now, who should and should not buy this plan
? This policy should definitely be purchased by those who
want to guarantee their child's future. They prefer not to take any risk and
want to save for the long term. And anyone
who believes in high risk and high returns should not buy this policy. They prefer to take too much
risk. This policy is not designed for those
who want to invest for the short term, for 2 years or 5 years. This entire
video shows how this plan
provides death benefit, money back, family income benefit, and maturity benefit, all guaranteed 100%. However,
if a customer wants these benefits without guarantees,
they want equity exposure, risk-adjusted returns,
and insurance coverage in this way, ICICI Prudential
Life Insurance already has a plan called
SIGNATURE ASSURE. I've already created a YouTube video about it,
a screenshot of which you can see here. You can watch this video on YouTube.
So, if you also want an equity-linked policy with similar features, you can also get it from ICICI.
This policy is available with . And if you also want a guaranteed policy,
the Smart Kit 360 policy is also available. If you
want to compare both plans in detail and purchase which one is best for you,
you can book a consultation at the number given below. To summarize the plan,
the true value of this plan is realized when life
doesn't go according to plan. If an unfortunate event occurs that
wasn't planned for, this plan is extremely useful.
A family tragedy has already occurred. Someone has died, and then another financial tragedy arises:
how will the children's education be managed? How will the household expenses be met? So,
this benefit is a great plan to ensure that one tragedy doesn't lead to another. This plan is ideal for
customers who want peace of mind, knowing from day one that they
will be purchasing this policy in 2026. I'm going to receive a fixed, guaranteed income. My child
is going to receive a fixed, guaranteed maturity, whether I'm alive or not. If
you enjoyed the video, please like,
share, and subscribe to my YouTube channel, Anil Rajpurohit Triple FH. If you'd like to compare child plans with similar
benefits, and from different companies—LIC, SBI, Tata, Bla, Max, Bajaj
, ICIC, HDFC—and purchase the best policy,
whether it's guaranteed, equity-based, even term insurance, or term plus ulti-pay
policy, please book a consultation at the number below. I'll provide you with
a detailed plan comparison based on your needs and your risk appetite,
which will be very helpful in your financial planning. Thank you so much.
Jai Hind. I'll leave you with a thought.
Yes, a question every parent should ask themselves when
making financial plans for their child's future. Whether it's a SIP, PPF, or any other
investment, we always hope for the best. But have we ever
stress-tested that plan? Have we considered
how it would perform if the worst happened, if the source of income suddenly stopped? Would it
be able to withstand that pressure? Would the child's goals still be met? Only an honest answer to this question
should help you choose the right financial plan.